New Delhi, India

🗷 hitesh.kumar61@yahoo.com | 😭 www.hitesh.one | 🖸 hiteshhedwig | 🛅 hiteshkumar17 | 💆 @rnnishard

"A healthy mind is an inquisitive mind."

### Personal Profile

As a self-taught and passionate individual, I am eager to pursue a Master's in AI. Currently, I am a seasoned Deep Learning Engineer with over three years of experience in AI. I am keen to delve deeper into research areas and push the boundaries for perception strategies on autonomous vehicles and robotics. My strong determination and vision for research have been further enhanced after working on projects involving Autonomous Vehicles, AI for Smart Cities, and Mars Rover prototype-like challenging and fruitful themes.

### Research Interests\_

- · Vision based Autonomous driving
- · Computer Vision on Robotics
- Deep Learning
- Visual odometry

## Relevant Professional Experience

**Euler Motors (EV startup)** New Delhi, India

DEEP LEARNING ENGINEER, COMPUTER VISION - AUTONOMOUS R&D

Aug. 2022 - Present

- · Key contributor in building real-time ADAS (Advanced Driver Assistance Systems) using pure C++; optimized for Nvidia Jetson Nano. Implemented forward/rear collision warnings and automatic braking system.
- · Led raw data curation and established semi-automatic data annotation system; expedited team processes, saving over two days.
- Trained and optimized lightweight object detection and segmentation models; achieved over 60% and 50% model size reduction, enhancing low-latency performance.
- Initiated and maintained production-level documented C++ code (ROS) for ADAS system; achieved <100ms inference times using GPU, 10Hz alert generation, and reduced hardware costs by over 65%.

SynergyLabs (AI startup) New Delhi, India

DEEP LEARNING RESEARCHER - R&D

July. 2021 - Aug. 2022

- Trained and customized classification & object detection models with data augmentation; achieved 14% increase in performance.
- Designed and implemented automatic number plate detection pipeline in Python to flag overspeeding vehicle.
- Developed Vehicle Detection System deployed on highways; attained <6% speed error in detection.
- Co-developed attention-based OCR model for license plates; achieved over 95% accuracy on standard plates.

SynergyLabs (AI startup) New Delhi, India Feb. 2021 - July. 2021

DEEP LEARNING INTERN - R&D

• Collaborated with founder in developing 'Automatic Traffic Counter System (ATCS)'; deployed across 300+ locations.

- Curated dataset for MobilenetV2 fine-tuning; reduced model size to 2MB, achieving 30% reduction.
- Debugged issues and maintained error resolution documentation, saving teammates 3+ hours.
- Developed ATCS product configuration UI with PyQT; reduced manual effort by 3x.

# Skills

Platform/Tools Linux, Docker, Google Cloud, ROS, CMake

**Frameworks** OpenCV, Pytorch, Tensorflow, CUDA, Numpy, Matplotlib, FFMPEG, Git

**Interests** Machine Learning, Deep learning, Computer vision, Robotics

ELP USB Cameras, IP Cameras, Nvidia Jetson Series, Raspberry Pi, Arduino, 2D Radar, 4D Radar, 2D Lidar, 3D Lidar, Intel Sensor/Hardware

HITESH KUMAR · CURRICULUM VITAE

Realsense, IR Sensor, Ultrasonic Sensor, Hall effect Sensor etc.

**Programming** C++, Python, Golang Languages English, Hindi, Korean

### Education

JANUARY 31, 2024

#### Delhi Technological University (formerly DCE)

Delhi, India 2016-2020

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

## **Extracurricular Activity**

Society of Robotics DTU India

 CORE MEMBER
 2016 - 2018

- Key organizer for University tech-fest; managed events like Robosoccer, Robofight.
- Mentored juniors in computer vision fundamentals and career pathways.

#### InfernoDTU (Project Mars Rover Prototype)

India 2018 - 2020

SOFTWARE HEAD (AUTONOMOUS)

- Led autonomous tech team (5+ members) in developing Mars Rover Prototype's autonomous features for competitive events.
- Utilized ROS in C++/Python for remote rover navigation.
- Implemented traditional computer vision techniques using OpenCV for obstacle detection and collision avoidance.

InfernoDTU (Gokart)IndiaMember2017 - 2018

- Developed TensorFlow-based CNN model for animal detection on roads.
- Designed real-time pedestrian detection algorithm using OpenCV for Raspberry Pi 4b.
- Enhanced lane detection algorithm for improved performance.

## Research Papers

Analytical and Computational Modelling of Go-Kart Powertrains - Hitesh Kumar\*, Aditya Natu, Kunal

2020 **Mathur,** International Journal of Mechanical and Production Engineering Research and Development (IJMPERD)

Estimation Of Surface Roughness in turning operations using Multivariate Polynomial Regression -

2020 Hrishabh Jha, Ashutosh Panpalia, Devanshu Suneja, Geetanshu Ashpilya, Hitesh Kumar\*, and Vijay Gautam, Advances in Industrial and Production Engineering

### **Certificates**

- 2023 Build a Modern Computer from First Principles: From Nand to Tetris (ongoing), Coursera
- 2023 Visual Perception for Self-Driving Cars (University of Toronto) (ongoing), Coursera
- 2020 Robotics: Aerial Robotics (University of Pennsylvania), Coursera
- 2019 Introduction To Self Driving Cars (University of Toronto), Coursera
- 2020 Data Visualization, Kaggle
- 2020 AWS Machine Learning Foundation Course, Coursera
- 2022 Robotics: Perception (University of Pennsylvania), Coursera
- 2019 Internet History, Technology, and Security, Coursera